

# Anirban Chakraborty

Full Stack Developer



## **Professional Summary**

Experienced in Full Stack Development for 4+ years and offering skills in JAVA, Spring Framework with REST Web Services. Experienced in working with React/NextJs project. Expert in handling and delivering projects using Agile. Complex problemsolver with analytical and driven mindset. Dedicated to achieving demanding development objectives according to tight schedules while producing impeccable code and accustomed to working with cross-cultural, global teams.



## **Work History**

2020-09 -Current

## **Application Developer**

Glanbia, Kilkenny

- Java 17
- Established TDD with Junit, Mockito
- Create REST APIs
- Worked on service migration from SOAP to REST
- Established CI/CD with Jenkins, SonarCube, Ansible
- Docker, Apache Kafka
- Experienced in using AWS EC2, S3
- Develop new React reusable components
- Testing components with Jest, Cypress
- Experienced in writing, debugging payment integration for applications
- End to end application integration experience
- DSA & Algorithm in-depth experience
- Enhanced frontend using HTML5 & CSS3
- Plugin integration experience like custom youtube player, one trust cookie banner
- Experienced using GA4, GTM
- Currently doing Scrum master alongside development
- Experienced to use JIRA boards for Scrum and Kanban
- Participated in design and planning exercises for future software rollouts
- Delivered support training to help customers learn key features of applications
- Guided team in layout modifications to improve functionality
- Worked closely with other team members in such tasks as troubleshooting and debugging
- Participated with clients in discussion meetings
- Collaborated with multidisciplinary teams to design and implement new technology



#### Address

Kilkenny Ireland

#### **Phone**

0899797745

#### E-mail

anirbanc6617@gmail.com

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/anirbanc17/

#### www

https://github.com/canirban



## **Technical Profile**

- Java
- SpringBoot
- React
- JS
- Jest
- Restful
- HTML & CSS
- JUnit
- ¡Query
- DevOps
- Git
- SonarQube
- Jenkins
- Agile & Scrum
- Docker

features

 Collaborated with stakeholders regarding project capabilities and limitations to deliver optimal functionality

### 2017-07 -2019-08

## Software Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services, Kolkata

- Wrote highly optimised code for new enhancements using Java, Spring
- Discussed project progress with customers, collected feedback on different stages and directly addressed concerns.
- Partnered with development team on product development and application support plans.
- Implemented various user-stories which consisted of executing complex functionalities as requested by client, for every sprint
- Did enhancements in frontend Js with ES6
- Email template build and added email trigger automation events for application
- Prepared cronjobs.
- Collaborated with clients to define solution requirements.



## Education

2019-05 -2020-05

## Master of Engineering: Computer and Communication System

University of Limerick - Limerick, Ireland

Core Modules: Java Programming, Software Engineering, Testing Framework, Digital Signal Processing, Real Time Systems, Communications & Security, Protocols and Host & Network Security, Multimedia communications, Web-Based Application Design, Information Theory & Coding, .

### 2013-04 -2017-05

## Bachelor of Technology: Electrical Engineering

Netaji Subhash Engineering College - Kolkata, India